questions_and_answers = [
    {'question': 'What is the SQL command used to add records to a relational database?', 'answer': 'insert'},
    {'question': 'A(n) ____ is used for intellectual property protection of a logo, word, or words.', 'answer': 'trademark'},
    {'question': 'Which has more capacity, a DVD SS DL or a DVD DS SL?', 'answer': 'DS SL (slightly)'},
    {'question': 'How many megabytes are in a gigabyte?', 'answer': '1,000'},
    {'question': 'The two file systems typically associated with Windows are what?', 'answer': 'FAT & NTFS'},
    {'question': 'Name the three types of interpreted languages.', 'answer': 'Scripted, scripting, markup'},
    {'question': 'To configure a wireless router, you should change the ______ and ______ passwords.', 'answer': 'Network (wireless) & admin'},
    {'question': 'To map out a program, you would use a(n) _______.', 'answer': 'Flowchart'},
    {'question': 'Which data type represents a single letter or number?', 'answer': 'Char'},
    {'question': 'Which gives the greatest mobility: wired, wireless, or cellular?', 'answer': 'Cellular'},
    {'question': 'Which network protocols are used to download email?', 'answer': 'POP3 & IMAP'},
    {'question': 'To make your hardware work, what type of software do you need?', 'answer': 'device driver (driver)'},
    {'question': 'The unique hardware address assigned to your network adapter is called the ______ ______.', 'answer': 'MAC address'},
    {'question': 'When setting up a wireless connection on a mobile device, what is the step after locating the SSID?', 'answer': 'Enter the wireless password'},
    {'question': 'What are four examples of nonrepudiation factors?', 'answer': 'Video, biometrics, signature, receipt'},
    {'question': 'Programming languages that are converted a single time into low-level code are called what?', 'answer': 'Compiled Languages'},
    {'question': 'If you want your Windows OS to be continually updated, what do you need to configure?', 'answer': 'Windows Update'},
    {'question': 'The central part of the operating system is called the _____.', 'answer': 'Kernel'},
    {'question': 'What type of software is not free and requires a license?', 'answer': 'Propietary (commercial)'},
    {'question': 'To protect a computer against viruses and spyware, install _______.', 'answer': 'Antimalware'},
    {'question': 'What are three advantages of SSD over HDD?', 'answer': 'Faster startup, faster read times, less power consumption and heat, silent, more reliable, less susceptible to shock damage, higher data density'},
    {'question': 'Two ways to track user actions on a system are what?', 'answer': 'Logs & web browser history'},
    {'question': 'Excessive, unwanted email is referred to as what?', 'answer': 'Spam'},
    {'question': 'The process of providing proper credentials to access a computer resource is called ______.', 'answer': 'Authentication'},
    {'question': '____ is an open-source workstation OS.', 'answer': 'Linux'},
    {'question': 'What is it called when Windows autodetects new hardware and installs the driver?', 'answer': 'Plug & Play'},
    {'question': 'What is the purpose of optical discs?', 'answer': 'Data storage (removable)'},
    {'question': 'Color inkjet printers use ink cartridges called _____.', 'answer': 'CMYK'},
    {'question': 'The three characteristics of an object in programming are what?', 'answer': 'Properties, attributes, and methods'},
    {'question': 'To retrieve raw, unformatted data from a database, use a(n) _____.', 'answer': 'Query'},
    {'question': 'When setting up a wireless connection on a mobile device, what is the step after turning on Wi-Fi?', 'answer': 'Locate the SSID'},
    {'question': 'The three types of accounts on a computer are what?', 'answer': 'Admin, user, guest'},
    {'question': 'Code that is for people to read and does not affect a program is called what?', 'answer': 'Pseudocode'},
    {'question': 'The three types of intellectual property protection are what?', 'answer': 'Trademarks, copyrights, and patents'},
    {'question': 'What are the two most popular broadband connection types?', 'answer': 'DSL & cable modems'},
    {'question': 'What is a GPU?', 'answer': 'Graphics Processing Unit'},
    {'question': 'What type of high-level language is read line by line every time it’s executed?', 'answer': 'Interpreted'},
    {'question': 'What type of processor is most likely to be found in small devices?', 'answer': 'ARM'},
    {'question': 'In addition to manufacturer documentation and websites, what are two external resources to check for technical help?', 'answer': 'Technical community groups, Internet search, and tech support'},
    {'question': 'What are two examples of markup languages?', 'answer': 'HTML & XML'},
    {'question': 'What is the SQL command used to modify data in an existing record in a relational database?', 'answer': 'UPDATE'},
    {'question': 'A(n) ____ is used for intellectual property protection of an invention.', 'answer': 'Patent'},
    {'question': 'Which type of programming data identifier can change?', 'answer': 'Variable'},
    {'question': 'Which type of programming data identifier does not change?', 'answer': 'Constant'},
    {'question': 'When assessing software compatibility, check what two things?', 'answer': 'Make sure it runs on your OS, and make sure you meet minimum hardware requirements.'},
    {'question': 'Versions of the ____ OS are named after sweet treats.', 'answer': 'Android'},
    {'question': 'Risks of using public workstations include what three things?', 'answer': 'Shoulder surfing, keyloggers (or other malware), unsecured wireless networks'},
    {'question': 'The identity which you are known by when you log in is your _______.', 'answer': 'User account'},
    {'question': 'A program that appears to be beneficial but is actually malware is called what?', 'answer': 'Trojan horse'},
    {'question': 'Which common computing device generally has the fastest processor and most memory?', 'answer': 'Server'},
    {'question': 'When a system runs out of RAM, what does it use next?', 'answer': 'Virtual memory'},
    {'question': 'What are two types of communications expansion cards?', 'answer': 'NICs (network interface cards) & modems'},
    {'question': 'What is the purpose of the CPU?', 'answer': 'Process data'},
    {'question': 'The three common Linux file systems are what?', 'answer': 'ext3, ext4, & XFS'},
    {'question': 'Microsoft’s workstation OS is called _______.', 'answer': 'Windows'},
    {'question': 'A program that runs on top of the OS and allows the user to issue commands is what?', 'answer': 'Shell'},
    {'question': 'What are three symptoms of adware?', 'answer': 'Constant pop-ups, home page (or browser) redirection, search engine redirection'},
    {'question': 'Word processing and spreadsheet programs are considered _____ software.', 'answer': 'Productivity'},
    {'question': 'Another name for the serial port is ____?', 'answer': 'RS-232'},
    {'question': 'Which two external connector types were developed by Apple?', 'answer': 'FireWire & Thunderbolt'},
    {'question': 'What is the low-level programming language best suited for direct hardware access?', 'answer': 'Assembly'},
    {'question': '_____ is the process of scrambling the data in user files so that others cannot read them.', 'answer': 'Encryption'},
    {'question': 'To use purchased software, you need a(n) ______ _______, which stipulates the conditions of use.', 'answer': 'Software license'},
    {'question': 'The _______ port was also called the printer port.', 'answer': 'Parallel'},
    {'question': 'Which type of data container can hold only one data type at a time?', 'answer': 'Array'},
    {'question': 'Which network protocol is used to upload email?', 'answer': 'SMTP'},
    {'question': 'Which data type represents several letters or numbers?', 'answer': 'String'},
    {'question': 'Which access control model uses security labels, classifications, and categories?', 'answer': 'Mandatory access control'},
    {'question': 'When configuring a wireless router, what should you upgrade at the end of the process?', 'answer': 'router firmware'},
    {'question': 'What is the purpose of RAM?', 'answer': 'Temporary data storage; it makes the computer faster'},
    {'question': 'Which type of common computing device will have a touchpoint built into it?', 'answer': 'Laptop'},
    {'question': 'The most common connector used today for keyboards and mice is ___?', 'answer': 'USB'},
    {'question': 'To make a file smaller in size or to package multiple files together in one archive, use _________ software.', 'answer': 'Compression'},
    {'question': 'A(n) ____ is used for intellectual property protection of a book or a song.', 'answer': 'copyright'},
    {'question': 'If your TCP/IP client wants to get on the Internet, which optional configuration parameter is required?', 'answer': 'Default gateway'},
    {'question': '______ is the feature that configures your computer with an IP address in the 169.254 range if it can’t find a DHCP server.', 'answer': 'APIPA'},
    {'question': 'What are the three network storage types?', 'answer': 'File server, NAS, and cloud'},
    {'question': 'What common computing device typically has a screen smaller than 7 inches in size?', 'answer': 'mobile phone'},
    {'question': 'What security concept asks the question, “Who are you?”', 'answer': 'Authentication'},
    {'question': 'The three tiers of a three-tier application architecture are what?', 'answer': 'Database layer, business logic layer, presentation layer'},
    {'question': 'What does Airplane mode do on a wireless device?', 'answer': 'Immediately dsables all wireless connections'},
    {'question': 'Asking users to reveal sensitive or personal information over the phone is referred to as _______ _________.', 'answer': 'Social engineering'},
    {'question': 'What are five examples of availability concerns?', 'answer': 'Denial of service, power outage, hardware failure, destructino, service outage'},
    {'question': 'The five categories of OSs are what?', 'answer': 'Workstation, server, mobile device, embedded, and virtual (or hypervisor)'},
    {'question': 'Which expansion card communicates with other computers over telephone lines?', 'answer': 'Modem'},
    {'question': 'Which backup storage location option is the fastest? Local, network, or cloud?', 'answer': 'Local'},
    {'question': 'The _____ service lets computers with private IP addresses get on the Internet.', 'answer': 'NAT'},
    {'question': 'What is the SQL command used to create queries?', 'answer': 'Select'},
    {'question': 'What are two locations from which you might receive an installation file?', 'answer': 'a CD-ROM from the manufacturer, or a download from the Internet.'},
    {'question': 'When users are allowed to assign their own permissions, that is known as a ______ access control model.', 'answer': 'Discretionary'},
    {'question': 'How often should you update your security software?', 'answer': 'At least once a week'},
    {'question': 'When setting up a wireless connection on a mobile device, what is the step after entering the wireless password?', 'answer': 'Verify Internet connectivity'},
    {'question': 'What is most secure: wired, wireless, or cellular?', 'answer': 'Wired'},
    {'question': 'Binary numbers can have the values of ___ or ___.', 'answer': '0 or 1'},
    {'question': 'What two TCP/IP configuration parameters are required to communicate on a network?', 'answer': 'IP address and subnet mask'},
    {'question': 'What is the name of the mode that immediately disables all wireless connections on a mobile device?', 'answer': 'Airplane mode'},
    {'question': 'Malware that self-replicates and carries a payload of other malware is called what?', 'answer': 'Worm'},
    {'question': 'Which type of data container is fixed in length?', 'answer': 'Array'},
    {'question': '_____ printers use a powdery plastic substance to create images.', 'answer': 'Laser'},
    {'question': 'Data such as pictures that have been tagged with metadata are known as ____ data.', 'answer': 'Semistructured'},
    {'question': 'What is the SQL command used to add, remove, or modify fields in a relational database?', 'answer': 'Alter'},
    {'question': 'What is the most common video connector, also used with televisions?', 'answer': 'HDMI'},
    {'question': 'Which type of key in a database table is required?', 'answer': 'Primary'},
    {'question': 'When a user types a password once and is given access to multiple systems, what is that called?', 'answer': 'Single sign-on'},
    {'question': 'Many companies will have passwords _____ periodically as part of a security policy.', 'answer': 'Expire'},
    {'question': 'Needing to provide a password and present a smart card to log in is an example of _____ ______.', 'answer': 'Multifactor Authentication'},
    {'question': 'Columns in a relational database are also called what?', 'answer': 'Fields'},
    {'question': 'Which expansion card would you plug speakers into?', 'answer': 'Audio/Sound card'},
    {'question': '______ IP addresses cannot participate on the Internet.', 'answer': 'Private'},
    {'question': 'The key combination of _______ lets a user lock their computer when they leave.', 'answer': 'ctrl + alt + delete'},
    {'question': 'What type of server is used exclusively as a server?', 'answer': 'Dedicated Server'},
    {'question': 'What is a PSU?', 'answer': 'Power Supply Unit'},
    {'question': 'What allows you to browse the Internet without your normal browser settings and identification?', 'answer': 'Private browsing'},
    {'question': 'The file system typically used by macOS is what?', 'answer': 'HFS'},
    {'question': 'The three application delivery methods are _______, _______, and ________.', 'answer': 'Locally installed, local network hosted, and cloud hosted'},
    {'question': 'Data arranged in columns and rows is referred to as _____ data.', 'answer': 'Structured'},
    {'question': 'The name of the round keyboard and mouse connector is ____?', 'answer': 'PS/2'},
    {'question': 'To harden a device, you can disable communications features such as ____ and ____.', 'answer': 'Bluetooth, NFC'},
    {'question': 'Malware that extorts those infected to pay a fee to remove the malware is called what?', 'answer': 'Ransomware'},
    {'question': 'Which expansion card produces images?', 'answer': 'Video card'},
    {'question': 'To ensure that your OS gets the most important security updates, even if you don’t know they were released, you should enable ______.', 'answer': 'Automatic updates (or Windows Update, or Software Update)'},
    {'question': 'Give two examples of IoT home automation devices.', 'answer': 'Thermostat & security system'},
    {'question': 'What type of biometric sensor is on newer mobile devices?', 'answer': 'Fingerprint scanner'},
    {'question': 'What IoT device is typically used with security systems?', 'answer': 'IP camera'},
    {'question': 'Rows in a relational database are also called what?', 'answer': 'Records'},
    {'question': 'Flash drives and NAS are examples of what?', 'answer': 'External storage devices'},
    {'question': 'What is the purpose of the motherboard?', 'answer': 'Connects all components together'},
    {'question': 'The name of the app store for iOS is called?', 'answer': 'iTunes'},
    {'question': 'What is the name of the feature that completes your name and address for you in web pages?', 'answer': 'Autofill'},
    {'question': 'Which TCP/IP service resolves host names to IP addresses?', 'answer': 'DNS'},
    {'question': 'What are the two network protocols used to access the Internet?', 'answer': 'HTTP & HTTPS'},
    {'question': 'What are the two network protocols used to access the Internet?', 'answer': 'Control Panel'},
    {'question': 'Which networking device connects networks to each other?', 'answer': 'Router'},
    {'question': 'Popular connectors for external hard drives are ________?', 'answer': 'USB, FireWire, eSATA, Thunderbolt'},
    {'question': 'Which two programming concepts are used to break code into smaller, reusable chunks?', 'answer': 'Functions & methods'},
    {'question': 'Air cooling for processors usually involves which two components?', 'answer': 'Heat sink & fan'},
    {'question': 'Telephone cables have a(n) _______ connector at the end.', 'answer': 'RJ-11'},
    {'question': 'To manage a hard drive in Windows, use the _____ utility.', 'answer': 'Disk Management'},
    {'question': 'In information security, a(n) _____ concern is one that involves ensuring the data is true and accurate.', 'answer': 'Integrity'},
    {'question': 'When users are assigned permissions based on job function and can’t be assigned permissions based on their user account, that is known as a ______ access control model.', 'answer': 'Role-based'},
    {'question': 'What are four examples of integrity concerns?', 'answer': 'Man-in-the-middle, replay attack, impersonation, unauthorized information alteration'},
    {'question': 'When configuring a wireless router, what should you do to the SSID?', 'answer': 'Change it from the default'},
    {'question': 'Two types of nonrelational databases are ____ and ____.', 'answer': 'Document and key/value'},
    {'question': 'A secure website requires a(n) _______.', 'answer': 'Valid certificate'},
    {'question': 'Which three external issues should you check for when troubleshooting a computer?', 'answer': 'Loose cables/connectors, power, & physical damage'},
    {'question': 'To remove temporary Internet files from your web browser, you should ______.', 'answer': 'Clear the cache'},
    {'question': 'What are the two types of data containers in programming?', 'answer': 'Arrays and vectors'},
    {'question': 'A problem in the coding of software that is used by an attacker is called what?', 'answer': 'An exploit'},
    {'question': 'Which expansion card might have its own GPU?', 'answer': 'Video card'},
    {'question': 'When rebooting a mobile device with biometric security enabled, what must you do to unlock the device?', 'answer': 'Enter the passcode'},
    {'question': 'What are three wireless networking technologies used today?', 'answer': 'Wi-Fi, Bluetooth, NFC'},
    {'question': 'What is the name of the logical computer address used by routers to make decisions on where to send packets?', 'answer': 'IP address'},
    {'question': 'What are some examples of object-oriented programming languages?', 'answer': 'Java, C++, Python, PHP, Perl, Ruby'},
    {'question': 'What is the name of the sensor that allows a mobile device to act as a compass?', 'answer': 'Magnetometer'},
    {'question': 'Which data type indicates a number with no decimal places?', 'answer': 'Integer'},
    {'question': 'The hard drive space used to augment system RAM is called what?', 'answer': 'Virtual memory'},
    {'question': 'A(n) ________ is a version of Linux.', 'answer': 'distribution'},
    {'question': 'A(n) ____ key is one that refers to data in another table in a database.', 'answer': 'Foreign'},
    {'question': 'The _____ user account should be disabled for security purposes unless it is being used.', 'answer': 'Guest'},
    {'question': 'File size and name are examples of what?', 'answer': 'File metadata'},
    {'question': 'What type of computer is used as both a server and someone’s workstation?', 'answer': 'Nondedicated server'},
    {'question': 'Which type of data container can store multiple data types at once?', 'answer': 'Vector'},
    {'question': 'Which data type indicates a number with decimal places?', 'answer': 'Float'},
    {'question': 'The default OS on an iPad or iPhone is ____.', 'answer': 'iOS'},
    {'question': 'If you need a notational system that has non-English letters, what do you need to use?', 'answer': 'Unicode'},
    {'question': 'Hexadecimal uses what numbers and letters?', 'answer': '0-9 & A-F'},
    {'question': 'Which networking device is used to connect computers together in a LAN?', 'answer': 'Switch'},
    {'question': 'Requiring another form of identification in addition to a password in order to log in is known as what?', 'answer': 'Multifactor authentication'},
    {'question': 'The three types of information used in multifactor authentication are what?', 'answer': 'Something you know, something you have, something you are'},
    {'question': 'Looking at someone’s computer to see sensitive information they type in or display is called what?', 'answer': 'Shoulder surfing'},
    {'question': 'Which operating system is named after big cats or California locations?', 'answer': 'Mac OS X'},
    {'question': 'Peripheral hardware requires a(n) ______ to be installed.', 'answer': 'Driver (device driver)'},
    {'question': 'What are two methods used to cool processors?', 'answer': 'Air & liquid'},
    {'question': 'To protect your security, you should limit the use of ______ on the Internet.', 'answer': 'PII (personally identifiable information)'},
    {'question': 'When assigning security permissions, always follow the _____ ______ model.', 'answer': 'Least privilege'},
    {'question': '______ is the process by which you provide your name and contact information to the software manufacturer.', 'answer': 'Registration'},
    {'question': 'What security concept determines what you can do on a network?', 'answer': 'Authorization'},
    {'question': 'The process of connecting two Bluetooth devices together for communication is called what?', 'answer': 'Pairing'},
    {'question': 'Which programming logic component uses if and else if statements?', 'answer': 'Branching'},
    {'question': 'Conferencing and instant messaging are considered _____ software.', 'answer': 'Collaboration'},
    {'question': 'To scroll down or change a page on a mobile device, which action do you use?', 'answer': 'Swipe'},
    {'question': 'What does the power supply do?', 'answer': 'Converts AC power to DC power for system components'},
    {'question': '_____ is the process of letting you use the software by linking it to your computer.', 'answer': 'Activation'},
    {'question': 'Which security concept ensures that users can’t deny that an event took place?', 'answer': 'Nonrepudiation'},
    {'question': 'The first step to storing files on a hard drive is to _____ the hard drive.', 'answer': 'Partition'},
    {'question': 'Which networking device is used on wireless networks to connect workstations to the network?', 'answer': 'Access point'},
    {'question': 'What are the four basic functions of an OS?', 'answer': 'Interface between the user and hardware and coordinate hardware components, provide environment for software to run, monitor system health, display file and directory structure'},
    {'question': 'Which programming logic component uses while statements?', 'answer': 'Looping'},
    {'question': 'To zoom in our out in a map on a mobile device, which action do you use?', 'answer': 'Pinch'},
    {'question': 'Twisted-pair network cables have a(n) _____ connector at the end.', 'answer': 'RJ-45'},
    {'question': 'Which networking device is a security barrier?', 'answer': 'Firewall'},
    {'question': 'What are three options for backup storage locations?', 'answer': 'Locally attached storage, network-attached storage, off-site/cloud'},
    {'question': 'To monitor system health in Windows, you would use _______.', 'answer': 'Performance Monitor'},
    {'question': 'What are some types of pointing devices?', 'answer': 'Mouse, touchpad, joystick, stylus pen, trackball'},
    {'question': 'To make sure you run consistent software backups, be sure to ______ them.', 'answer': 'Schedule'},
    {'question': 'Which command creates a duplicate file in a new location on the hard drive?', 'answer': 'Copy'},
    {'question': 'To kill a process in Windows, use the _____ utility.', 'answer': 'Task Manager'},
    {'question': 'The oldest computer display devices are _____.', 'answer': 'CRTs'},
    {'question': 'Three common gesture-based interactions for mobile devices are what?', 'answer': 'Tap, swipe, & pinch'},
    {'question': 'What is the SQL command used to define a new database or table in a database?', 'answer': 'CREATE'},
    {'question': 'Which type of data container can have dynamically adjusted length?', 'answer': 'Vector'},
    {'question': 'In Windows, drivers are managed in which utility?', 'answer': 'Device manager'},
    {'question': 'When setting up a wireless connection on a mobile device, what is the step after verifying wireless capabilities?', 'answer': 'Turn on Wi-Fi'},
    {'question': 'BlackBerry devices are known for having _____ keyboards.', 'answer': 'Physical'},
    {'question': 'What adds functionality to a web browser?', 'answer': 'Add-on or extension'},
    {'question': 'What is a DDR3 DIMM?', 'answer': 'a memory module (RAM)'},
    {'question': 'What is the name of a file a website downloads to your computer to identify you?', 'answer': 'Cookie'},
    {'question': 'Which security concept is responsible for tracking user actions on a system?', 'answer': 'Accounting'},
    {'question': 'Who should you contact to get updated device drivers?', 'answer': 'The hardware manufacturer'},
    {'question': 'Data such as pictures, emails, and text is referred to as _____ data.', 'answer': 'Nonstructured or unstructured'},
    {'question': 'A(n) ______ uniquely identifies a record in a relational database.', 'answer': 'Primary key'},
    {'question': 'What should you not do if you receive a hyperlink or attachment in a suspicious email?', 'answer': 'Click it'},
    {'question': 'In programming, what are the two types of data identifiers?', 'answer': 'Variables and constants'},
    {'question': 'When setting up a wireless connection on a mobile device, what is the first step?', 'answer': 'Verify wireless capabilities'},
    {'question': 'In information security, a(n) _____ concern is one that involves ensuring the data is accessible when users need it.', 'answer': 'Availability'},
    {'question': '_____ Wi-Fi networks are unsecure and should not be used.', 'answer': 'Open'},
    {'question': '___________ replaced CRTs as the most common type of display device.', 'answer': 'Flatscreens'},
    {'question': 'What are five features of file systems?', 'answer': 'Compression, encryption, permissions, journaling, and naming rules'},
    {'question': 'What should be true about a web browser’s version before you use it?', 'answer': 'It should be the most current version'},
    {'question': 'What determines the rules of how long a file name can be?', 'answer': 'The file system'},
    {'question': 'What type of RAM chips do laptops use?', 'answer': 'SODIMM or MicroDIMM'},
    {'question': 'A Boolean data type represents which two values?', 'answer': 'True or false'},
    {'question': 'Google’s mobile OS is called ____.', 'answer': 'Android'},
    {'question': 'To install or run a purchased application, you need a(n) _____.', 'answer': 'Product Key'},
    {'question': 'What type of IoT device is best suited to watch television over the Internet?', 'answer': 'Streaming media device'},
    {'question': 'The rules and structure of a relational database are called what?', 'answer': 'Schema'},
    {'question': 'To preserve your data in the case of hardware failure, you should _______ your data.', 'answer': 'Back up'},
    {'question': 'The current Macintosh OS is called _____.', 'answer': 'macOS'},
    {'question': 'List examples of authentication factors.', 'answer': 'Password, PIN, one-time password, software token, hardware token, biometrics, specific location, security questions'},
    {'question': 'The current fastest Wi-Fi standard is _____.', 'answer': '802.11ac'},
    {'question': 'The first place to check when you have a device failure or question is where?', 'answer': 'The manufacturer\'s documentation or website'},
    {'question': 'What type of software license requires you to pay every year?', 'answer': 'Subscription'},
    {'question': 'Which type of computing device is specialized to play video games?', 'answer': 'Gaming console'},
    {'question': 'Malware that attaches itself to an executable program and does damage to your computer is called what?', 'answer': 'Virus'},
    {'question': 'Which optical disc stores the most data?', 'answer': 'BD-ROM (Blu-ray)'},
    {'question': 'How do you prevent extra web browser windows from appearing when a website wants them to?', 'answer': 'Pop-up blocker'},
    {'question': 'Two examples of OS interfaces are ____ and _____.', 'answer': 'Console/command line and GUI'},
    {'question': 'What is the data notational system that contains only English letters, numbers, and symbols?', 'answer': 'ASCII'},
    {'question': 'A device that has multiple external hard drives and network capability is called what?', 'answer': 'Network-attached storage (NAS)'},
    {'question': '____ are display devices that let you input as well.', 'answer': 'Touchscreens'},
    {'question': 'Which two options can be used to back up an iPhone or iPad?', 'answer': 'iTunes or iCloud'},
    {'question': 'The first commonly used digital video connector was what?', 'answer': 'DVI'},
    {'question': 'Which programming language category is used to write scripts?', 'answer': 'Scripting'},
    {'question': 'What type of programming language is designed to pull data from a database?', 'answer': 'Query'},
    {'question': 'What is the SQL command used to remove records from a relational database?', 'answer': 'DELETE'},
    {'question': 'In a file system, files are organized and placed into what?', 'answer': 'Folders (or directories)'},
    {'question': 'What is the name of the sensor that allows the screen to rotate when you turn a mobile device?', 'answer': 'Gyroscope'},
    {'question': 'Limitations put on a field in a database are called _____.', 'answer': 'Constraints'},
    {'question': 'To run a 64-bit OS, you need a(n) _____ CPU.', 'answer': '64-bit'},
    {'question': 'Other than enabling WPA2, WPA, or WEP, what two wireless network security options can you use?', 'answer': 'Disable SSID broadcasts and enable MAC filtering'},
    {'question': 'If you want to prevent a button on a web page from working on a web browser, what should you do?', 'answer': 'Deaactivate client-side scripting or use a script blocker'},
    {'question': 'Which TCP/IP service automatically configures clients with an IP address?', 'answer': 'DHCP'},
    {'question': 'How many bytes are in a kilobyte?', 'answer': '1,000'},
    {'question': 'Malware that tracks your Internet activity and sells that information to marketers is called what?', 'answer': 'Spyware'},
    {'question': 'What is the name of the component that controls communication between the processor and memory?', 'answer': 'Chipset'},
    {'question': 'A programmer wants to write code that directly accesses the computer\'s hardware. Which is the best type of language for the programmer to use?','answer': 'Assembly'},
    {'question': 'Which type of card might have a joystick port?', 'answer': 'Audio/Sound card'},
    {'question': 'What file system does not allow you to rename a file when it is open?', 'answer': 'NTFS and FAT32'},
    {'question': 'What is a SuperSpeed device?', 'answer': 'USB 3.x'},
    {'question': 'What option can you configure on your workstation to increase security when you leave your desk?', 'answer': 'Lock the computer / Screen saver password'},
    {'question': 'Which of the following is not a form of intellectual property protection? Trademark, Patent, Copyright, Authentication.', 'answer': 'Authentication'},
    {'question': 'What two types of connectors can a joystick have?', 'answer': 'PS/2 and USB'},
    {'question': 'According to the ITIL framework, a ____ is the structured information about all the services and service offerings of a service provider, relevant for a specific target audience.', 'answer': 'Service Catalog'},
    {'question': 'A ____ is capable of resolving technical issues but does not liaise with other resolver groups, service providers or departments.', 'answer': 'Help Desk'},
    {'question': 'Your manager has indicated that there are limited resources available today, so you should prioritize resolving urgent requests first. What is the process known as?', 'answer': 'Triage'},
    {'question': 'Which of these troubleshooting steps takes place soonest in the troubleshooting methodology?', 'answer': 'Reproduce the problem'},
    {'question': 'You have followed the troubleshooting methodology on a specific ticket and failed to resolve the problem. You believe additional expertise is required. What is the next step?', 'answer': 'Escalate the ticket'},
    {'question': 'Which document explains how the company network, website or system may be used and sets guidelines as to how it should be used?', 'answer': 'Acceptable Use Policy (AUP)'},
    {'question': 'What does this line of bash script do: #!/bin/bash and what is it called?', 'answer': 'It is called a shebang and it tells the shell which interpreter to use for the script'},
    {'question': 'what needs to be added to the following command to install Python on an Ubuntu Linux computer: ____ apt-get install python3', 'answer': 'sudo'},
    {'question': 'What type of expansion card allows your computer to communicate over telephones?', 'answer': 'Modem'},
    {'question': 'Is a scanner an input device?', 'answer': 'Yes'},
    {'Mary, an admin, creates a field and designates it to hold integer data.  Joe, a user, tries to enter his name into the field, but it doesn\'t let him save the data.  What is this an example of?', 'answer': 'Constraint'},
    {'question': 'At work, you want to ensure that interns can only access the files specifically created for them and no other files.  Which term is most correct in describing this configuration?', 'answer': 'Least Privilege'},
    {'question': 'When is it most appropriate to perform a restoration procedure using a known good baseline system image?', 'answer': 'The computer is infected with a virus that antivirus failed to remove'},
    {'question': 'You\'ve copied a useful Powershell script to a recently-deployed Windows 10 computer, but it won\'t run.  What should you check first?', 'answer': 'Check that Set-ExecutionPolicy is unrestricted'},
    {'question': 'What is the purpose of Microsoft Active Directory?', 'answer': 'Centrally organize and administer user identities and computers'},
    {'question': 'What command shows all running tasks in Windows 10?', 'answer': 'Tasklist'},
    {'question': 'When disk space is low, Windows will record this event as a(n) ________.', 'answer': 'Warning'},
    {'question': 'Which of the following is NOT an event type recorded by Windows? Issue, Error, Information, or Warning?', 'answer': 'Issue'},
    {'question': 'What is uppermost folder in the Windows Registry?', 'answer': 'Hive'},
    {'question': 'What is NOT addressed by a standard operating procedure (SOP)?', 'answer': 'Why'},
    {'question': 'What Linux-friendly character is used for filtering results of a Powershell operation?', 'answer': '| (pipe)'},
]


